Let's take a look at the completed 2D platformer game.
Here it's running full screen on my Windows PC.
Here we see our playable character in the center,
looks like a green pig character.
We've got an enemy character off to the side there in that blue shell,
create objects and different pickup objects around the world.
The pickups look like little strawberries that you can get.
We also see a tile-base level design with
all these platform areas that we can walk around on,
and at the top of the screen,
we see the user interface with a Score,
the Instructions, and a Restart button.
Now the score starts at zero,
but it'll go up by one each time I collect one of these pickups and
the instructions are shown to help the user understand how to play using the arrow keys.
After we collect the first strawberry,
the use arrow keys will disappear,
giving us a little bit more screen real estate so we
can enjoy the tile-base level design.
The restart button can be clicked at any time
and restarts a fresh game session. Let's take a look at that.
Here with my mouse, I can click the Restart button
and our character disappears and restarts again.
Let's take a look at the controls in the audio of the game.
As I click Up Arrow, I can jump,
and we hear a little pop sound as I jump
up and a little sound as I land on the platform again.
Then I can use the Right and the Left Arrow keys to walk around.
When I collect this strawberry,
we'll hear a little sound confirming I've gotten some points,
and we'll see the score update in the user interface.
Nice chime. I'll jump up and collect another one here.
As I'm jumping around,
you can see in the background,
there's this sunset sky color and also the cloud.
Each of those layers moves a little bit different
than the way that the camera follows our character around the screen,
so it gives a little bit of a depth effect,
makes the level look a little bit more alive because
that clouds slightly different has just a nice, smooth, polished effect.
I can move that crate around as we saw before.
In case you wanted to create some puzzles in the games,
you'd be able to jump up on that,
and the game also has complete win and loss conditions.
Let's see how it would work. I'll click Restart again, and here,
I'll try to capture some of
the strawberries that we need but there's an enemy in my way here.
Now, if I touch the enemy,
I'll die and get reset.
Let's say I tried to jump, but I didn't,
and I hit the enemy,
so I get reset there,
or if as the player,
you get stuck between two platforms and you fall down off the world,
you also hit that red area there which kills you and gets you reset,
so now the player has a clear path to collect all the strawberries,
but also some tension created by the enemies and being able to fall off things,
so we'll see how I'm able to play around
the world and collect all of the different pickups.
Hopefully, this time, I make it.
I died that time. We'll try one more time here.
This is a little tricky to get so I'll get a running start.
Now, I'll be careful not to hit our enemy there.
This is going to be the eighth one that I collect,
and that'll be it for the old game.
It should finish when I collect this last strawberry.
The text at the top updates to you win.
We can see our score is eight out of eight.
Just to keep the graphics alive,
I have the playable character,
continue to breathe here in mid air as a victory,
and the input is disabled.
I'm not able to move around which is a nice confirming sign that the game is over.
At any time, including now,
the player can hit the restart button and be able to restart and play again.
That's it. That's the complete game.